<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Us on COPIM</title>
    <link>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Us on COPIM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aims</title>
      <link>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/aims/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/aims/</guid>
      <description>COPIM will develop a significantly enriched not-for-profit and open source ecosystem for OA book publishing that will support and sustain a diversity of publishing initiatives and models, particularly within the Humanities and Social Sciences (HSS), in the UK and internationally. The project aims to:
 Remove hurdles preventing new and existing OA book initiatives from adopting OA workflows by 1) building open-source, community-based infrastructures that support the publication of OA books, and 2) establishing and consolidating partnerships between HE institutions and OA book publishers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consortium</title>
      <link>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/consortium/</guid>
      <description>about consortium&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funders</title>
      <link>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/funders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/funders/</guid>
      <description>COPIM is supported by the Research England Development Fund (REDF) as a major development project in the Higher Education sector with significant public benefits. The RED Fund commits up to £25 million in annual funding. This money aims to drive innovation in research and knowledge exchange in higher education. The award covers £2,202,947 of the project’s total budget, which also includes £538,755.62 in partners’ own contributions.
COPIM is also supported with a grant of £800,000 from Arcadia, a charitable fund of Lisbet Rausing and Peter Baldwin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory board</title>
      <link>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>about advisory board&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact</title>
      <link>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copim.ac.uk/about-us/impact/</guid>
      <description>The project consolidates existing relationships among the partners into a major strategic collaboration that will enhance the impact of research in England. At the same time, COPIM promotes a community-based approach for the collaboration of academic institutions and industry stakeholders. Finally, it develops innovative approaches for knowledge exchange activities to facilitate sustainable and workable transitions to an open publication ecosystem for monographs and to ensure a diverse ecology of publishers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>